SOURAV MONDAL

5+ Years of experience

Email: sourav7systems@gmail.com **Mobile:** (+91) 9008441627

INTRODUCTION

Senior Software Engineer with 5+ years' experience in web and cli application designing, coding, testing and support. I am Passionate in crafting best in class application with the cutting-edge technologies. I believe in Readable, Reusable, Testable and Tested code.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Juniper Networks, Bangalore (August 2013 – May 2018)

Cerner Corporation, Bangalore (May 2018 – Present Date)

SKILL SET

Primary Skill	Ruby, Ruby on Rails, ReactJs, Redux, Java, JAX-RS, Javascript, PostgreSQL
Languages	Ruby, Javascript, Java, Python, Perl
Interested to work with	Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Java, JAX-RS, ReactJs, Redux, Python
Testing Framework	RSpec, Junit, Mockito, Jest
Frameworks/Libraries	Ruby on Rails, ReactJs, Redux, JAX-RS, JQuery, ExtJS, Flask
Databases	PostgresSQL, MySQL, SQLite
Internet Technologies	HTML, CSS, Ajax, JSON, YAML, REST, SOAP
Web Server	Apache, Webrick, Puma, Passenger, Nginx, Uwsgi
Development Tool	Rubymine, IntelliJ, Pycharm
Source Control	Git, SVN, CVS
Operating Systems	Mac OS X, Linux (Ubuntu), Windows
Deployment	Capistrano

EDUCATION

Degree: MCA

Institution: PES Institute of Technology

Percentage: 78.87

PROJECT DETAILS & EXPERIENCE

1. LabSequence May 2018 - Preset Date **Role: Full Stack Developer** Lab Sequence is a hosted laboratory solution designed to optimize and automate the complex processes associated with molecular diagnostic and sequencing workflows. **Key Responsibilities** ☐ Full stack development Designing, Coding, Debugging, Testing and Reviewing **Technologies Used**: ReactJs, Redux, Ruby on Rails, Java8, JAX-RS 2. Etrans Nov 2014 - Apr 2018 **Role: Full Stack Developer Etrans** is a tool to track test scripts review, regression harness status, test scripts metrics, test scripts coding standard and test scripts review status in their transitioning cycle. **Key Responsibilities** Full stack development Figured out few poor performing elements and fine-tuned them Designing, Coding, Debugging, Testing, Supporting and Reviewing **Technologies Used**: Ruby, Rails, ExtJS, Postgres, Python, Perl, Capistrano 3. Ti-Lint/ Toby-Lint Sept 2013 - Apr 2018 **Role: Backend Developer** Ti-Lint/Toby-Lint are the tools developed in Perl and Python respectively which has the set of rules. All the test scripts have to satisfy those rules before it runs in production. **Key Responsibilities** Designing, Coding, Testing and Supporting Backend cli development

Technologies Used: Perl, Python

4. Systest Script Sync

September 2016 - Apr 2018

Role: Full Stack Developer

Systest Script Sync is the tool to sync scripts from repository to different Geos based on user demand, so that the scripts become accessible to regression harness tool to run them in different

Enhanced the tools to support customization and configuration according to user requirement

Geos.

Key Responsibilities

 $oxed{oxed}$ Designing, Coding, Testing and Supporting

Technologies Used: Perl, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Jquery